[JAO SPEAKS SIARGAONON] Good morning.
What’s the occasion?
[JAO] Nothing.
I just wanted to give you flowers.
“Smell me now, dye me later”?
I put a lot of thought into that.
[HAN BIN] You’re almost there, Pearl.
You have the right words.
You just need the confidence to say it.
I will finish this some other time.
[PEARL] I just need to get ready for our celebration later.
[PEARL] Katig’s anniversary should be fun!
[CAROL] I hope they like it.
- [HAN BIN SPEAKS SIARGAONON] Morning! - Good morning!
[HAN BIN SPEAKS SIARGAONON] Morning!
[JAO] Happy anniversary!
You see this?
[KARA] They all have jobs because of you.
[KARA] And you see this crazy girl?
[KARA] This crazy girl has a job that she loves
because of a crazy guy like you.
You guys all mean so much to me.
[CROWD CHEERING AND CHANTING]
[JAO] Wait!
[TANTAN] Sir Jao...
You don’t have a place to stay.
I’m all alone.
We’ll help you.
Starting today, you can call me Uncle Jao, too.
Sounds good?
- That can wait! - Good evening, sir.
[MAN] Do you have a room?
Caitlyn?
[JAO] Come on, Kara. Let’s head back out.
Caitlyn!
- [MAN] Wait. - [JAO] Hey.
Sorry, I don’t think Kara wants to talk to you.
Kara?
Her name is Caitlyn.
The fact that you don’t even know that name…
That means this is none of your business, man.
Well, I know her enough to say that she doesn’t want to talk to you.
And who are you, exactly?
Jeremy.
Her ex-fiancé.
Look, I’m not trying to cause any trouble.
I didn’t even know Caitlyn was here.
I just came as a tourist, man.
[JAO] Kara?
[ALON BY JL]
[FIRE CRACKLING] [LOUD MUSIC IN THE BACKGROUND]
[LOUD MUSIC IN THE BACKGROUND]
[CAROL] Hello!
- [HAN BIN] Hello! - Mom!
Pearlita. Hello!
Why don't you join us there?
- Dance some more! - [PEARL LAUGHS]
- [HAN BIN] No, thanks. - [CAROL] This dance.
- [PEARL LAUGHS] - [CAROL] Didn’t you want to dance?
- Or you want another… beer? - [ARIEL] Mom!
[ARIEL] Jeremy’s here. Kara’s ex!
Oh! Okay, uh…
I’ll take care of it. You guys stay here.
[ARIEL] Go on. It’s her ex.
[CAROL] Is he handsome?
- [ARIEL] Go. - [CAROL] Fine. Stay here.
Oh no... Kara’s ex-boyfriend?
- [ARIEL] Ex-fiancé! - [PEARL GASPS]
Exes belong in the past.
[PEARL] Even if…
You know about him already?
A little.
Caitlyn is very secretive, but…
sometimes I hear her and our mom talking about Jeremy.
Wait, so…
Kara’s real name is Caitlyn?
- Yeah. - Yeah!
You didn’t know?
No.
[PEARL] What?
How can you not know, Sir Han?
Kara always talks about that, even to our guests!
Actually, all of our guests.
How she changed her name to
Kara because “karajaw” means “awesome”.
Yeah, because her life started to become awesome when she lived here.
I mean,
I didn’t know all of this.
When I met Kara,
she’s already Kara.
I didn’t know she has a secret identity.
Han Bin oppa, it’s not a secret identity!
It’s more like a rebranding.
[ARIEL] Yeah.
How about you, Han Bin oppa?
Do you have a secret identity?
- Me? - [ARIEL] Yeah.
Or a…
new rebranding that you’re not telling us?
No!
I’m just Han Bin.
Han Bin oppa.
- Han Bin oppa. Sir Han. - [HAN BIN] Yes.
I think we need
hot chocolate and suman. (Sticky rice cake)
[SIARGAONON] Sounds amazing!
- Good idea! - [HAN BIN] Let’s go?
- Yes, Ariel will help you! - Yes! I will!
- Yeah, let’s get... - Let’s go!
- You’re not coming? - No.
[KARA BREATHING HEAVILY]
[JAO] Kara?
[RAPID FOOTSTEPS ON STAIRS]
[KARA CRYING SOFTLY]
[KARA BREATHING HEAVILY]
So, that’s Jeremy?
Why is he here? Is he looking for me?
No.
He said he was surprised to see you here, too.
Uh…
[KARA CRYING SOFTLY]
He said he wants to talk to you.
Just to see how you’re doing.
I don’t want to talk to him.
- Kara. - [KARA BREATHING HEAVILY]
It’s been over seven years.
Why does...
[KARA BREATHING HEAVILY]
Why does Jeremy still seem to have power over you?
Jao’s outside waiting for you.
He wanted to know if you’re okay.
Do you want to talk to him?
Not yet, Carol. I just want to be alone.
Want me to bring you a beer?
[KARA CRYING SOFTLY]
Kara.
Caitlyn.
Whoever you may be...
Kara deserves to be happy.
[KARA CRYING SOFTLY]
[CAROL] Caitlyn deserves...
to be free.
[CAROL] Hm?
[KARA BREATHING HEAVILY]
I'll get the beer.
[KARA CRYING SOFTLY]
[FIRE CRACKLING]
You don’t have to say anything.
I just want you to know that I’m here.
[KARA EXHALES]
I was still a kid when my parents split up.
Eventually, they both started new families.
But neither of them wanted to take me in.
I ended up with my grandmother.
[KARA BREATHES DEEPLY]
I felt so...
unwanted.
My grandmother loved me.
She gave me everything.
But something was missing.
So I kept looking for it in other people.
Until, eventually…
I met Jeremy.
I was his executive assistant at his...
family’s steel and mining company.
And then...
that was it.
He made me feel like
I was his whole world.
And for someone who felt so unwanted her whole life,
that meant everything.
His parents were kind to me, too.
[KARA SNIFFS]
They really treated me like I was one of their own.
I also felt so...
needed.
I was so happy because I thought,
“Finally.”
"Finally, I have a family."
[KARA SNIFFS]
All of that…
All of that became my life raft.
[KARA BREATHING SHAKILY]
And no matter what happened,
I will never let go of that raft.
[KARA SNIFFS]
Even when Jeremy was already cheating on me.
[KARA SNIFFS AND BREATHES HEAVILY]
Where’s Ariel?
Charging his phone.
Okay. Oh, it’s hot.
Mhmm! Sikwate! (Traditional Filipino hot chocolate drink)
Perfect for the vibes,
[SIARGAONON] for sure!
[PEARL HUMMING]
Sir Han?
Why is your face like that?
Pearl.
I want to tell you something.
Oh...
That sounds so serious.
I’m getting nervous.
Yeah.
You should feel nervous.
Because…
the deadline for the application is due soon.
You really should start working on it.
Yes, Sir Han. Actually,
with our talk earlier,
I’m now excited to do the essay.
I know. But please,
like I told you,
write about you instead of me.
Don’t worry, Sir Han. I’ll take care of it.
Actually,
I have a question for you.
What?
Why are you so nice to me?
But I stayed.
I stayed.
[KARA SNIFFS]
Even though he kept cheating on me.
I was just there.
[KARA SNIFFS]
I even said yes when he asked me to marry him.
[KARA SOBS]
Because I thought I could fix it.
I’d waited my whole life for something like that.
I finally got it.
[KARA SNIFFS]
And I became terrified of losing it.
[KARA BREATHES SHAKILY]
I didn’t want to feel unloved again.
So, I did everything for them.
[KARA CRIES]
I told you I love deeply.
No one’s judging you here.
What they did to me was awful.
[KARA BREATHES DEEPLY]
[KARA SCOFFS]
[KARA BREATHES SHAKILY]
Until now, I still haven’t forgiven myself for it.
[KARA CRIES]
I don’t know why I let that happen to me.
[KARA BREATHES SHAKILY]
Kara.
[KARA BREATHES DEEPLY]
You have to give credit to yourself.
Because you walked out of that relationship.
It doesn’t matter how long it took you, you got out.
[KARA SNIFFS]
You saved yourself.
[JAO] Don’t you realize?
You were the life raft.
[KARA CRIES SOFTLY]
You saved yourself the moment you walked out of that relationship.
So stop punishing yourself.
[KARA BREATHES SHAKILY]
[JAO] I've made my share of...
questionable decisions, too.
Decisions that...
challenged my beliefs.
But that’s life.
We’re only human.
So, please, Kara.
You have to forgive yourself.
Don’t feel guilty for wanting to be loved.
Because you found it.
You found you.
You found it on this island.
[KARA BREATHES SHAKILY]
You were broken and shattered into pieces,
but look at you now.
Look at the life you’ve built here, the community you’ve fostered.
The influence that you have on me,
on all of us on this island.
[KARA EXHALES]
You didn't just find yourself.
You reinvented yourself.
If that isn’t self-love, then I don’t know what is.
I’m hard to love, Jao.
I’m ready to love you, Kara.
[JAO] Do you want to know what I told Ruth?
[JAO] I'm ready to love you, Kara.
Sir Han, why are you being so nice to me?
I think I forgot something.
- [HAN BIN CLEARS THROAT] - Sir Han!
Okay.
[HAN BIN SPEAKS KOREAN] The thing is…
[SIARGAONON] Are you planning to stay here, sir?
I think I might stay here for good.
There it is!
The curse got you, too!
I really fell hard for Kara.
[JEREMY] I just wanted to talk to you because...
I just wanted to check on you.
I was…
I was so afraid of you.
[KARA] I was completely crushed.
[JEREMY] What’s going on? It’s been years, Caitlyn.
I thought that was in the past.